Let the song of the sea sway your heart...
Song of the Sea is a family, animation, fantasy film directed by Tomm Moore.
The story of the last Seal Child’s journey home.
After their mother’s disappearance, Ben and Saoirse are
sent to live with Granny in the city.
When they resolve to return to their home by the sea, their journey becomes a race against
time as they are drawn into a world Ben knows only from his mother’s folktales.
But this is no bedtime story; these fairy folk
have been in our world far too long.
It soon becomes clear to Ben that Saoirse is the key to their survival.
Ben (voice), played by David Rawle.
Conor / Mac Lir (voice), played by Brendan Gleeson.
Bronach (voice), played by Lisa Hannigan.
Granny / Macha (voice), played by Fionnula Flanagan.
Saoirse (voice), played by Lucy O'Connell.
Ferry Dan / The Great Seanachaí (voice), played by Jon Kenny.
Song of the Sea (Irish: Amhrán na Mara) is a 2014 animated fantasy film directed by Tomm
Moore and written by Will Collins based on an original story by Moore.
An international co-production between Ireland, Belgium, Denmark, France and Luxembourg, the film follows the story of a 10-year-old Irish boy named Ben (David Rawle) who
discovers that his mute sister Saoirse—whom he blames for the apparent death of his mother—is a selkie, who has to free faerie creatures from the Celtic goddess Macha.
Like other Cartoon Saloon films, the animation is a combination of traditional hand-drawn and
computer-generated types, with a domination of the stylistically naïf form of the first being dominant.
This follows the style set in The Secret of Kells, with it mainly appearing with a flat or
2-dimensional aspect, but also incorporating some 3-dimensional image modelling.
Aptly, the imagery of the animation is composed in the form of water-colours,
especially in the backgrounds and in the narrative flashback scenes.
The film began production soon after the release of The Secret of Kells and premiered at the 2014
Toronto International Film Festival on 6 September in the "TIFF Kids" programme.
The film was acclaimed by critics and had a
limited release in certain countries.
It won the Satellite Award for Best Animated or Mixed Media Feature and European Film Award for Best Animated Feature
Film, as well as nominations for Best Animated Feature at the 87th Academy Awards and 42nd Annie Awards.
The film is the second installment of Moore's "Irish Folklore Trilogy", following his
previous film The Secret of Kells (2009) and later the film Wolfwalkers (2020).
The Irish-language version was produced by Macalla with funding from TG4 and the Broadcasting
Authority of Ireland, with selected cinemas in Ireland screening it from 10 July 2015.
Brendan Gleeson and Fionnula Flanagan reprised their
respective roles in this version.
The DVD with the Irish audio can be bought in Cartoon Saloon's online store.
The film explores themes of fairy tale, lighthouse, folk
music, lighthouse keeper   , ireland.